Hello friends, did you know that there are
many benefits of taking insurance at a young age?
That's why today we're going to talk about the
benefits of health insurance at an early age. If you're
thinking about family planning, then taking out a health insurance
plan will protect your financial well-being.
Additionally, taking out health insurance will make
you feel more secure,
knowing you have financial support to cover any
unexpected medical
expenses. Relying
solely on a corporate health insurance policy is
n't a wise decision. Therefore, it's crucial to have your own health
insurance plan.
Health insurance from a company is temporary;
it lasts only as long as
you're associated with that company. The
insurance ends as soon as you leave the company.
However, with a personal health plan, you're always
secure. This video is especially
for those in their early 30s who are
wondering why they should take out health insurance
now. Let's now
tell you about the six most important benefits of health insurance,
after which you can decide whether to take out health insurance.  You will
definitely prefer to take
low premium rates for extensive
coverage. You want more coverage at a lower premium. You can
definitely get it if you
take a policy cover at a young age.
As you all know that as the age
increases, the premium amount also gets higher
because the risk increases.
In younger age, the risk is less,
hence it is easier to get a bigger cover amount.
Secure from lifestyle diseases.
Unforgotten due to changing lifestyle,
FinanciallyExpress.com knows that if
health issues are
unforeseen,
then no worries. Easy to overcome the
waiting period. Every health insurance policy has a
waiting period. Whenever you
take a policy, it
provides only accidental cover on the first day. For
example, slow-growing illnesses like
hernia, cataract, stone, all these diseases
mostly have a waiting period of up to two years. So,
if you take a policy at a young age,
your waiting period will be over timely
and you
can also easily claim the treatment of the disease. Tax
benefits of your own health insurance  The
policy also offers you tax benefits under section
8D. If you are an insured member and
your age is less than 60 years, you can get
tax amount up to Rs.
25,000. And if the insured person is 60 years old, you
can get tax exemption up to Rs.
50,000. No pre-policy checkup
required. Another advantage of buying health insurance at a young age is
that you do
not need a pre-policy medical checkup
because the chances of having any medical history at a young age are
less.
Offers peace of
mind. Why do we buy a health insurance policy?
Because there is no unforgotten future.